OBAIDUL HOQUE CHOWDHURY | DEVELOPER, DATA SCIENTIST AND ANALYST

Doha, Qatar | +974 33663337 | obaid.hoque@icloud.com | www.linkedin.com/in/obaidhoque

A diligent and collaborative professional with a background in research and analytics. I am adept at finding the best possible analytical solution individually and while collaborating with a team. I have conducted independent research on Autism Spectrum Disorder and implementation of AI chatbots. My other interests are related to Derivatives and Financial Modelling.

Keywords: Data Scientist, Data Analyst, Python, SQL, R Programming, Tableau, SAS Programming, MS Excel, HTML, CSS, Django

EDUCATION

- University of Derby United Kingdom (August 2019) M.Sc.; Big Data Analytics; Grade: Distinction
- **Qatar University** Qatar (Spring 2016) B.B.A; Management Information System; CGPA: 3.01
- M.E.S Indian School Doha, Oatar (March 2012) High School Certificate: 90%

Senior Secondary Certificate: 80%

CERTIFICATIONS

- . Responsive Web Design – 04/2020 (credential)
- Oracle SQL Certification 01/2020 (credential)
- Tableau Desktop Specialist 08/2019 (*credential*)
- Certified R Programmer 03/2018 (*credential*)

CAREER SUMMARY

FULL-TIME

October 2018 - February 2020

Parcelforce Worldwide (Royal Mail UK), Coventry

Data Scientist

Outline

Provision of a set of data analytics modules that was integrated into the company's business intelligence platform. Analysis of platform data using analysis tools such as Tableau and R and drawing meaningful conclusions/generating reports by identifying facts and trends in client behavior. These reports, generated using R Markdown, R Shiny and Tableau presentation module were presented to top level management for effective decision making.

June 2014 - July 2018

Venus Travels LLC, Doha

IT Analyst

Outline

Managing technology requirements of the company to ensure the company has the right tools to achieve competitive advantage in the travel & tour industry. Tasked to analyze marketing trends using Data analysis and visualization Techniques.

June 2013 – September 2013

Integrated Information Systems - Middle East (FBQ Holding), Doha Junior Logistics Intern

Outline

Was required to research on key variables as per the requirements of colleagues. Delivered high quality research along with good written work which was well received by peers.

FREELANCE CONTRACTS

December 2018 – March 2019

Remote Consultant @ Sheldon Flanders Financial Services: Drew a status report on the implementation of Intelliflo (CRM) into the company's core operation structure. Consulted on the efficacies of the system and generated documentation/user manual for employees to integrate into core operational requirements of the system.

July 2019 – September 2019

Remote Consultant @ Zest AI: Designed research strategies for data collection, analysis and processing to be used by a newly developed non-linear and dynamic algorithm model for underwriting credit risk.

July 2013 – Present

Remote Web Developer: Many years of experience developing frontend user friendly and interactive websites using HTML. CSS, WordPress and Django web framework.

WEBSITES

- Github.com Software Development using R and Python
- Kaggle.com Data Analysis projects, Machine-Learning Projects, Data Visualization Projects
- Tableau.com Dashboards and interactive visualizations
- Codepen.io Frontend templates

References available on request.